moneysmart.gov.au 2019-12-17

# Privacy | ASIC's MoneySmart

Any information gathered when you use ASIC's MoneySmart website or apps will not be disclosed or distributed further without your consent.

We comply with the Australian Privacy Principles in the [Privacy Act 1988 (Cth)](http://www.austlii.edu.au/au/legis/cth/consol_act/pa1988108/ "Privacy Act 1988 \(Cth\)") which regulates the collection, storage, quality, use and disclosure of personal information.  We also follow the Federal Government website guidelines issued by the [Office of the Australian Information Commissioner](https://www.oaic.gov.au/ "Office of the Australian Information Commissioner").

The MoneySmart website is run by the Australian Securities and Investments Commission (ASIC).  Please refer to [ASIC's privacy policy](http://www.asic.gov.au/about-asic/dealing-with-asic/summary-of-asic-privacy-policy/ "ASIC's privacy policy") for information about how ASIC handles personal information, your rights to seek access to and correct personal information and how to complain about breaches of your privacy by ASIC.

  * Collection of statistical information
  * Collection, use and disclosure of personal information
  * Publishing unclaimed money data
  * Cookies
  * Internet security risks

## Collection of statistical information

ASIC's MoneySmart website collects information, without identifying factors, for statistical and research purposes, and to help improve our tools. This information can include: 

  * The user's server address
  * The top level domain name e.g. .com or .gov etc
  * The date and time of the visit
  * The pages accessed and documents downloaded
  * Responses to questions
  * Items added to lists
  * The previous site visited
  * The type of browser used

For example, we may include your visit to our superannuation calculator in preparing aggregate statistical information such as '20% of the people who used ASIC's MoneySmart superannuation calculator explored making extra contributions to their superannuation'.

Other than for statistical purposes no attempt will be made to identify your visit or browsing activities except in the unlikely event of an investigation.  In an investigation, a law enforcement agency may inspect the internet service provider's log files with a warrant.

## Collection, use and disclosure of personal information

ASIC's MoneySmart will only retain your personal information with your consent, via a prominent button that you may choose to click.  Any time this occurs, you will be informed of the purpose for which the information is being collected.

ASIC's MoneySmart will not disclose or distribute your personal information without your consent, except where required to by law, for example by court order.

Moneysmart will only retain your personal information with your consent, via a prominent button that you may choose to click. Any time this occurs, you will be informed of the purpose for which the information is being collected.

### Google Analytics

In addition to web service logs, we use Google Analytics (including the Advertising Features), which are web analysis services provided by Google Inc. ('Google').

Reports obtained from Google Analytics are used to improve the efficiency and usability of this website. They do not contain user identifiable information. Google Analytics uses cookies to help analyse how users interact with this site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. The Advertising Features is a function within Google Analytics to get more advanced information about our users, including:

  * user demographics
  * user interests
  * frequency of visits

For more information on how Google uses the data collected, visit [Google's Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ "Google's Privacy Policy") and [Google Analytics Terms of Service.](https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/terms/us/ "Google Analytics Terms of Service") To opt-out and prevent your data from being collected by Google Analytics, you can download [Google's opt out add-on.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Google's opt out add-on.")

### MoneySmart personal profile

When you set up a personal profile in ASIC's MoneySmart (so that you can save and retrieve your results for calculators and apps) you will only be required to supply your email address. All other details you might choose to supply are optional.

Your email address will only be used for the purpose for which you provided it and will not be given to any outside party.

You can amend all the information in your MoneySmart personal profile.

### MoneySmart Tips enewsletter

By subscribing to MoneySmart Tips, you consent to your email address being provided to Campaign Monitor, our enewsletter service provider. [Campaign Monitor's privacy policy](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies/) explains how they handle personal information, including their overseas storage practices.

Your email address is only used to deliver MoneySmart Tips to you. You can use an alias or generic email address. You can access current and past editions MoneySmart Tips or unsubscribe on our website.

## Publishing unclaimed money data

Unclaimed money records are published on ASIC's MoneySmart website so people can find their lost money.  ASIC offers a free service that people would otherwise be charged for by commercial money finding businesses. ASIC is required or authorised by law to publish this information.

## Cookies

This website may use cookies (small pieces of information exchanged between your web browser and a website server) for online surveys.

## Internet security risks

ASIC's MoneySmart website employs a range of security measures to protect against data breaches, including firewalls, security patches, regular security testing and data encryption.  This website complies with the Australian Government Protective Security Policy Framework and Information Security Manual.

As there may be security risks in sending information via the internet, you should assess these potential risks when deciding whether to use our online services.

If you have any concerns about your privacy when using this website, email us at [feedback@moneysmart.gov.au](mailto:info@moneysmart.gov.au "info@moneysmart.gov.au") or phone the ASIC Infoline on 1300 300 630.

Last updated: 09 Oct 2019
